Antioch, California

(925) 389-1294 Michaelpettet80@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Former fraud investigator and experienced professional with a demonstrated history of working in the Information Services Industry. Currently a SQL database administrator emphasizing in Big Data Analytics, Forensic Analysis and Risk Assessment. Strong work ethic and integrity with a firm belief in Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR).

SKILLS/ CERTIFICATIONS

- Operations/Personnel Management
- Compliance/Quality Control/Audit
- Quantitative Analysis
- Computer Programming (VBasic, SQL)
- Fraud Examinations
- Big Data Analytics
- SiSense Data Modeler
- Advanced SQL for Data Scientists
- SQL Fundamentals
- CISCO Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Microsoft (Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Project Manager)

WORK EXPERIENCE

SQL Production Support Administrator (Remote) – **ONE LEGAL LLC** April 2018 – NOW

Provide real-time monitoring of Microsoft SQL Server databases that support One Legal's content offerings. Work with Production Team to improve/optimize the applications usage of database resources while proactively maintain the overall health of the database servers. Provide on call 24x7 as required by on-call schedule and/or necessity of database dependent teams who may need support outside of regular business hours. Configure, implement and provide tier 1, 2 and 3 support for incident resolution. Design, implement and maintain low to moderately complex databases, access methods, access time, device allocation, validation checks, organization, protection and security, documentation and statistical methods. Maintain

database dictionaries, monitor standards and procedures and integration of systems through database design. Define file organization, indexing methods and security procedures for specific user applications. Execute ad-hoc queries and generate reports for users in a timely manner. Provide project status updates describing the state of assigned deliverables, accomplishments, and significant risk items. Estimate work duration and detailed tasks for input to project schedules.

Specific Accomplishments:

- Scaled deployment of New Relic across Production and UAT environments to capture and remove any system generated errors
- Identified severe Database deficiencies and worked with Sr. Management to procure resources and Engineering capital to resolve the issues
- Creating custom API using Postman to acquire data, transaction status, etc. from non-network Servers
- Use previous fraud prevention experience and forensic analysis methods to track and deter malicious users and/or content (Encryption/API/SQL)

Engineering Analyst (Consultant) – **CELERITY CONSULTING GROUP** April 2016 – April 2018

Follow pipeline (WOG) engineering methodologies and complete engineering calculations based on client procedure and standards. Research and review technical documents, online or in hard copy, to capture key data. Perform research and perform data entry; manipulate, validate, and format data in Excel or Access. Perform spreadsheet analyses, and summarize and report on results. Initiated SQL data capturing standards and reporting capabilities in regards to Project Management and Client data. Scan and copy documents, as needed. Maintain tracking logs for data and documents from point of collection to return/delivery. Follow data processing specifications. Following methodologies while also making suggestions for process improvement during data/document review and analysis. Perform first-pass engineering calculations and apply client procedure/standards to the review. Research engineering-related codes and best practices and serve as engineering resource for team.

Public Information Officer (Intern) – **UMBRELLA OF HOPE** June 2014 – June 2015

Developed funding sources to augment existing donations by locating private grants as well as research many others for the non-profit group. Maintain UOH eligibility and approved status with 'Maddie's Fund' guidelines as grant recipient. Some of the bi-weekly tasks included promoting through media channels such as 'Facebook' and 'Twitter'. Reached larger audiences and quadrupled the reach of Facebook posts. Additionally, other weekly tasks included clerical and data entry. Data regarding the animals was processed and stored digitally. Drove digital presence through proactive outreach to prospective institutional and corporate benefactors. Used the sales process to effectively target, and initiate contact, for donations and other grants by conducting sales calls, and making similar presentations.

accuracy, and compliance and raise potential risks and concerns, including deficiencies in funding. Liaise in time-sensitive manner with sales, processing, servicing, and capital markets teams regarding suitability and risk of processed loans. Create and issue independent compliant loan approval decisions. Maintain working knowledge of investor guidelines and policies. Mentor processing team on underwriting deficiencies. Complied with all company policies, procedures, and regulations.

Forensic Analyst/Fraud Examiner II – PMI MORTGAGE INSURANCE August 2003 – April 2007

Researched industry specific information from outside sources, which included conversations with Borrowers, industry publications, area libraries, references from other banks, credit agencies, as well as accessing information through the Internet. Processed authorizations used to obtain records. Sorted or filed deposition transcripts. Filed legal files and mail into categorical storage while maintaining coordinated digital legal mail search lists. Assisted Senior File Clerk and Claims Manager in training new staff. Perform short and long-range planning in support of existing and future requirements to enhance the systems. Provide support to the acquisition of data requirements for two systems. Review software design, change specifications, and plans against contractual and/or process requirements. Document and maintain complex requirements using standardized requirements templates (trace-ability matrix, SQL Project).

EDUCATION

CSU East Bay – BA: Public Administration; Business Administration Minor **Los Medanos College** – AA: Behavioral and Social Science